Guide to the Edwin and Terry Murray Collection of Role-Playing Games, 1972-2017 RL.00924
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Edwin and Terry Murray Collection of Role-Playing Games
1972-2017
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Murray, Edwin, and Terry Murray (collectors)
RL.00924
270 Linear Feet
Edwin L. and Terry A. Murray, brothers residing in Durham, North Carolina, have been collectors of comic books and other pulp culture for forty years. Collection includes role-playing game boxed sets, miniatures, card sets, role-play game magazines and literature, campaign guides, modules, and rule books.
Approx. 13,000 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. However, drop-in game play is not possible with this collection. Please contact Special Collections with questions about the appropriate use of this material.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the Rare Book, Manuscript, and Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Edwin and Terry Murray Collection of Role-Playing Games was received by the Rare Book, Manuscript, and Special Collections Library as a gift in 2002, 2010, and 2012.
Historical Note
Table-top role-playing games (RPGs) are a type of game where players create or assume the role of various characters and collaborate to imagine and build a story or quest. Each players' characterization offers guidelines and expectations for the abilities and tendencies of their character, and their proposed actions succeed or fail based on the game's established rules and statistics. One player may serve as a gamemaster to guide fellow players through the game and introduce new challenges or twists to the story.
Modern role-playing games emerged in the 1970s, with the first commercially available game, Dungeons & Dragons, published in 1974. It quickly became very popular, leading to copycats and competitors as well as enabling the development of RPG supporting material, such as campaign sets, miniatures and playing pieces, new literature, and fan magazines. Other popular games quickly followed, such as Advanced Dungeons and Dragons in 1977, Traveller in 1977, RuneQuest in 1978, Call of Cthulhu in 1981, and James Bond in 1983.
RPGs continued to grow and evolved through the late 1980s and 1990s. General game systems emerged, allowing for a single set of rules that worked with any setting. Another notable milestone was the release of Magic: The Gathering in 1993, which proved very popular and resulted in more spin-offs and competition in the field of collectible card games. Early computer games frequently adopted or mimicked RPG rules, eliminating the need for a gamemaster and increasing the game's speed. Many contemporary video games share their terminology, settings, and game mechanics with pen-and-paper RPGs.
Collection Overview
This collection includes thousands of game books, boxed sets, figurines, cards, magazines and serials. It also includes a small amount of manuscript material from the Murrays' own campaign notes and records. The materials have been divided into series based on format: Boxed Games (BG); Modules, Manuals, and Campaign Volumes (M); Miniatures and Pieces (P); Cards (C); Serials (S); and Manuscripts (MS). Within each series, materials have been sorted into their various game worlds and settings as best as possible. Along with Box and Volume numbers, barcodes for each item are included to ease research requests from Duke's offsite storage facility. Due to the vast number of games and the wide variety of research interests for this collection, a downloadable spreadsheet is available for researchers interested in browsing and sorting the games in different ways, such as by year or by box.
Download RPG spreadsheet
Please note: The collection contains loose parts such as dice, tokens, figurines, cards, etc. Some materials may be sealed in original packaging. Packaged materials in Miniatures series are intended to remain in sealed packaging. Please consult Research Services staff for assistance with removal of other materials from sealed packaging. Please return materials to original packaging whenever possible. Consult Research Services staff for assistance if materials cannot be returned to original packaging.
The Boxed Games (BG) series includes games from a range of worlds, as well as a large number of general games that date from the early 1970s to the mid-2000s. Large sub-series within the Boxed Games series include game settings and worlds like Dungeons & Dragons, Forgotten Realms, James Bond, DragonLance, RuneQuest, Star Trek, and Supremacy; but, there are many more from a large number of different systems. Boxed Games typically include campaign books and characterization sheets, grids or maps for game play, die, and rule books.
The Modules, Manuals, and Campaign Volumes (M) series is the largest series in the collection, with over 2300 distinct volumes from numerous game worlds and settings. The series includes a variety of publications, ranging from traditional modules with a plot and characters included, to manuals with lists of creatures or characters, to reference guides for various game worlds. Many companies published only volumes, with no accompanying boxed game, and so there are a large number of titles that have no correlation to the Boxed Games series. The largest game worlds or settings represented in this series are Advanced Dungeons & Dragons, Call of Cthulhu, Cyberpunk, Dungeons & Dragons, Forgotten Realms, Middle-Earth, and Traveller; but, there are many, many more from different game worlds as well as independent, one-time games.
The Miniatures and Pieces (P) series includes packaged and loose miniatures collected by the Murrays from a number of different companies. Most are generic and not attached to a particular game or game brand, although there are hundreds that were intended for playing with games like Advanced Dungeons and Dragons, Call of Cthulhu, DC or Marvel Superheroes, or Lord of the Rings. Along with metal miniatures, the series also includes other various types of gameplay aids, including settings guides, grids, and miscellany. A portion of this series consists of unpackaged, handpainted miniatures that have been specially housed for preservation.
The Serials (S) series contains fanzines and magazines collected by the Murrays relating to RPGs and RPG culture. Most magazine runs are incomplete and date from the late 1970s to the mid-2000s; the boxlist includes details about which issues are present in the collection.
The Cards (C) series includes cards from several years of Magic: The Gathering, as well as smaller amounts of cards of other games such as Legend of the Five Rings, New Aeon, Sim City, Spellfire, On the Edge, and Jyhad.
d20 modern (Game); Chill (Game); Castle Falkenstein (Game); Call of Cthulhu (Game); Lord of the Rings (Game); Fantasy games; Earthdawn (Game); Dungeons and Dragons (Game); Ravenloft (Game); Middle-Earth (Game); Magic: The Gathering (Game); RuneQuest (Game); Ars Magica (Game); Traveller (Game); Star Trek: The Role Playing Game (Game); Marvel Comics Group; DC Comics, Inc.; Murray, Edwin L.; Murray, Terry A., 1953-
- Boxed Games, 1972-2007; 82 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Series includes 484 boxed game sets for role-playing games like Dungeons and Dragons, Advanced Dungeons and Dragons, Call of Cthulhu, Al-Qadim, Car Wars, Traveller, James Bond, and Star Trek. A boxed set typically includes maps and grids, character guides, encounter playbooks, a die, and other literature to be used for creating new or altered worlds within a particular game.
  Arrangement note
  Contents have been listed alphabetically by game world or campaign, and within each world, chronologically by date. General games that have no identifiable "world" are listed at the end in alphabetical order. Barcodes are included with each title to better assist box requests from off-site. A downloadable spreadsheet is available for researchers who are interested in sorting or browsing the games in a different way.
  - 2300, 1
    - Star Cruiser (GDW), 1987 (Box BG80)
  - Ace of Aces, 2
    - Ace of Aces (Nova Game Designs, Inc), 1980 (Box BG60)
      Scope and Contents
      World War I Aerial Combat Game
    - Ace of Aces (Nova Game Designs, Inc), 1981 (Box BG60)
      World War I Air Combat Game
    - Ace of Aces: Wingleader (Nova Game Designs, Inc), 1988 (Box BG60)
      World War II Air Combat Game
  - Advanced Dungeons and Dragons, 3
    - Battle System: Fantasy Combat Supplement (TSR, Inc.), 1985 (Box BG71)
      Advanced Dungeons and Dragons
    - Bloodstone Pass (TSR, Inc.), 1985 (Box BG40)
    - Castles: A 3-Dimensional Game Accessory (TSR, Inc.), 1990 (Box BG71)
      Advanced Dungeons and Dragons 2nd Edition
    - Council of Wyrms (TSR, Inc.), 1994 (Box BG71)
    - Dragon Mountain (TSR, Inc.), 1993 (Box BG71)
  - Advanced Dungeons and Dragons 2nd Edition, 4
    - Deck of Priest Spells (TSR, Inc.), 1992 (Box BG33)
    - Monstrous Compendium: Volume One (TSR, Inc.), 1989 (Box BG32)
    - Wizard Spell Cards (TSR, Inc.), 1992 (Box BG28)
  - Advanced Squad Leader, 5
    - Blood Reef: Tarawa (The Avalon Hill Game Company), 1999 (Box BG77)
    - Croix de Guerre (The Avalon Hill Game Company), 1992 (Box BG78)
    - Doomed Battalions (The Avalon Hill Game Company), 1999 (Box BG78)
    - Hedgerow Hell (The Avalon Hill Game Company), 1987 (Box BG77)
    - Hollow Legions (The Avalon Hill Game Company), 1989 (Box BG78)
    - Kampfgruppe Peiper I (The Avalon Hill Game Company), 1993 (Box BG77)
    - Kampfgruppe Peiper II (The Avalon Hill Game Company), 1996 (Box BG77)
    - Operation: Watch Tower (Multi-Man Publishing), 2001 (Box BG81)
    - Partisan! (The Avalon Hill Game Company), 1987 (Box BG78)
    - Pegasus Bridge (The Avalon Hill Game Company), 1997 (Box BG77)
    - Red Barricades (The Avalon Hill Game Company), 1989 (Box BG77)
    - Shifting Sands: The Campaign for North Africa (Multi-Man Publishing), 2006 (Box BG81)
    - Starter Kit number 1 (Multi-Man Publishing), 2004 (Box BG81)
    - Starter Kit number 2 (Multi-Man Publishing), 2005 (Box BG81)
    - Starter Kit number 3 (Multi-Man Publishing), 2006 (Box BG81)
    - Streets of Fire (The Avalon Hill Game Company), 1985 (Box BG77)
    - The Last Hurrah (The Avalon Hill Game Company), 1988 (Box BG77)
    - Valor of the Guards (Multi-Man Publishing), 2007 (Box BG81)
    - West of Alamein (The Avalon Hill Game Company), 1988 (Box BG78)
    - Yanks (The Avalon Hill Game Company), 1987 (Box BG78)
  - Al-Qadim, 6
    - A Dozen and One Adventures (TSR, Inc.), 1993 (Box BG2)
    - Assassin Mountain (TSR, Inc.), 1993 (Box BG1)
    - Caravans (TSR, Inc.), 1994 (Box BG1)
    - Cities of Bone (TSR, Inc.), 1994 (Box BG1)
    - City of Delights (TSR, Inc.), 1993 (Box BG1)
    - Corsaurs of the Great Sea (TSR, Inc.), 1994 (Box BG2)
    - Golden Voyages (TSR, Inc.), 1992 (Box BG2)
    - Land of Fate (TSR, Inc.), 1992 (Box BG2)
    - Runed Kingdoms (TSR, Inc.), 1994 (Box BG2)
    - Secrets of the Lamp (TSR, Inc.), 1993 (Box BG2)
  - BattleTech, 7
    - AeroTech: The BattleTech Game of Fighter Combat (FASA Corporation), 1986 (Box BG60)
    - Battledroids: A Game of Armored Combat (FASA Corporation), undated (Box BG76)
    - BattleForce: Small Unit Actions in the 31st Century (FASA Corporation), 1987 (Box BG60)
    - BattleTech Reinforcements 2: Additional Units for BattleTech (FASA Corporation), 1992? (Box BG60)
      The Return of Kerensky
    - BattleTech: A Game of Armored Combat (FASA Corporation), 1985 (Box BG60)
    - BattleTech: A Game of Armored Combat (FASA Corporation), 1992 (Box BG60)
    - BattleTroops: A Game of Urban Man-to-Man Combat in the BattleTech Universe (FASA Corporation), 1989 (Box BG60)
    - Powerhits BattleTech (Activision), 1992 (Box BG60)
      Includes floppy disks for 3 BattleTech games: The Crescent Hawk's Inception, The Crescent Hawks' Revenge, and MechWarrior
  - Birthright (ADD), 8
    - Birthright: Campaign Setting (TSR, Inc.), 1995 (Box BG9)
    - Birthright: Cities of the Sun (TSR, Inc.), 1995 (Box BG9)
    - Birthright: Havens of the Great Bay (TSR, Inc.), 1996 (Box BG9)
    - Birthright: The Rjurik Highlands (TSR, Inc.), 1996 (Box BG9)
  - Boot Hill, 9
    - Boot Hill: 3rd Edition Wild West Role-Playing Game (TSR, Inc.), 1974 (Box BG9)
    - Boot Hill: Role-Playing Game of the West (TSR, Inc.), 1979 (Box BG9)
  - Call of Cthulhu, 10
    - Call of Cthulhu: Fantasy Role-Playing in the Worlds of H.P. Lovecraft (Chaosium Inc.), 1981 (Box BG62)
    - Cthulhu by Gaslight (1890s) (Chaosium Inc.), 1986 (Box BG1)
    - Horror on the Orient Express (1920s) (Chaosium Inc.), 1991 (Box BG1)
    - Masks of Nyarlathotep (Chaosium Inc.), 1984 (Box BG1)
    - Spawn at Azathoth (1920s) (Chaosium Inc.), 1986 (Box BG1)
  - Car Wars, 11
    - Aeroduel: Aerial Combat in the 21st Century (Steve Jackson Games), 1990 (Box BG61)
      Car Wars supplement
    - Boat Wars: Boats, Aquabikes, Hovercraft and More! (Steve Jackson Games), 1988 (Box BG61)
    - Car Wars (Steve Jackson Games), 1985 (Box BG61)
    - Car Wars: The Card Game (Steve Jackson Games), undated (Box BG61)
    - Tanks: Military Vehicles for the Battlefields of the Future (Steve Jackson Games), 1990 (Box BG61)
  - Challenger series, 12
    - Champions of Mystara: Heroes of the Princess Ark (TSR, Inc.), 1993 (Box BG66)
      Dungeons & Dragons
    - Wrath of the Immortals (TSR, Inc.), 1992 (Box BG66)
  - Conan, 13
    - Messanyia - City of Riches (Mongoose Publishing), 2003 (Box BG76)
    - Shadizar - City of Wickedness (Mongoose Publishing), 2003 (Box BG76)
  - Cyberpunk, 14
    - Cyberpunk: The Roleplaying Game of the Dark Future (R. Talsorian Games Inc.), 1980 (Box BG23)
    - Land of the Free: Cyberpunk (R. Talsorian Games Inc.), 1994 (Box BG1)
  - Dark Sun (ADD), 15
    - City by the Silt Sea (TSR, Inc.), 1994 (Box BG69)
    - Dark Sun (TSR, Inc.), 1995 (Box BG69)
    - Dark Sun: Face the Fire of the Dark Sun (TSR, Inc.), 1991 (Box BG69)
    - Mind Lords of the Last Sea (TSR, Inc.), 1996 (Box BG69)
    - The Ivory Triangle (TSR, Inc.), 1993 (Box BG69)
  - DC Comics, 16
    - DC Heroes: Role Playing Game Featuring the New Teen Titans (), 1985 (Box BG11)
  - Doctor Who, 17
    - The Doctor Who: Role Playing Game (FASA Corporation), 1985 (Box BG11)
  - DragonLance, 18
    - Citadel of Light (TSR, Inc. (Wizards of the Coast)), 1998 (Box BG70)
    - Fifth Age (TSR, Inc.), 1996 (Box BG70)
      DragonLance: Fifth Age
    - Heroes of Defiance (TSR, Inc.), 1997 (Box BG70)
    - Heroes of Sorcery (TSR, Inc. (Wizards of the Coast)), 1997 (Box BG70)
    - Heroes of Steel (TSR, Inc.), 1996 (Box BG70)
    - The Last Tower: The Legacy of Raistlin (TSR, Inc.), 1996 (Box BG70)
    - Wings of Fury (TSR, Inc. (Wizards of the Coast)), 1998 (Box BG70)
  - DragonLance (ADD), 19
    - DragonLance: Monstrous Comendium: Appendix (TSR, Inc.), 1989 (Box BG30)
    - Dwarven Kingdoms of Krynn (TSR, Inc.), 1993 (Box BG67)
    - Heroes of Hope (TSR, Inc. (Wizards of the Coast)), 1997 (Box BG71)
    - Tales of the Lance (TSR, Inc.), 1992 (Box BG67)
  - DragonQuest, 20
    - DragonQuest: An Experience in Heroic Adventures (Simulations Publications, Inc.), 1980 (Box BG14)
    - DragonQuest: An Experience in Heroic Adventures: Great New Second Edition Master Set (Simulations Publications, Inc.), 1981 (Box BG14)
  - Dungeonquest, 21
    - Dungeonquest (Games Workshop), 1987 (Box BG7)
    - Dungeonquest: Catacombs (Games Workshop), 1987 (Box BG7)
    - Heros for Dungeonquest (Games Workshop), 1987 (Box BG7)
  - Dungeons & Dragons, 22
    - Dungeons & Dragons (TSR, Inc.), 1977 (Box BG66)
      Basic Set, Third Printing (May 1978)
    - Dungeons & Dragons (TSR, Inc.), 1980 (Box BG66)
      Expert Set
    - Dungeons & Dragons (TSR, Inc.), 1983 (Box BG66)
      Basic Rules, Set 1
    - Dungeons & Dragons (TSR, Inc.), 1983 (Box BG66)
      Expert Rules, Set 2
    - Dungeons & Dragons (TSR, Inc.), 1984 (Box BG66)
      Companion Rules, Set 3
    - Dungeons & Dragons (TSR, Inc.), 1985 (Box BG66)
      Master Rules, Set 4
    - Dungeons & Dragons (TSR, Inc.), 1974-1979 (Box BG66)
      Original Collector's Edition
    - Dungeons & Dragons: Hollow World (TSR, Inc.), 1990 (Box BG66)
      Campaign Set
  - Earthdawn, 23
    - Earthdawn: Barsaive (FASA Corporation), 1993 (Box BG49)
    - Earthdawn: Parlainth: The Forgotten City (FASA Corporation), 1994 (Box BG49)
    - Earthdawn: Sky Point & Vivane (FASA Corporation), 1995 (Box BG49)
  - Elfquest, 24
    - Elfquest: The Official Roleplaying Game (Chaosium Inc.), 1984 (Box BG62)
  - Forgotten Realms, 25
    - Campaign Set (TSR, Inc.), 1987 (Box BG2)
    - Campaign Setting (TSR, Inc.), 1993/1994 (Box BG2)
    - Cities of Mystery (TSR, Inc.), 1989 (Box BG2)
    - City of Splendors (TSR, Inc.), 1994 (Box BG2)
    - City System (TSR, Inc.), 1988 (Box BG2)
    - Elminster's Ecologies (TSR, Inc.), 1994 (Box BG2)
    - Empress of the Shining Sea (TSR, Inc.), 1998 (Box BG2)
    - Forgotten Realms Campaign Setting (TSR, Inc.), 1993 (Box BG68)
    - Kara-Tur: The Eastern Realms (TSR, Inc.), 1988 (Box BG3)
    - Lands of Intrigue (TSR, Inc.), 1997 (Box BG3)
    - Maztica (TSR, Inc.), 1991 (Box BG3)
    - Menzoberranzan (TSR, Inc.), 1992 (Box BG3)
    - Netheril: Empire of Magic (TSR, Inc.), 1996 (Box BG3)
    - Spellbound (TSR, Inc.), 1995 (Box BG72)
    - The Horde: Barbarian Campaign Setting (TSR, Inc.), 1990 (Box BG3)
    - The North: Guide to the Savage Frontier (TSR, Inc.), 1996 (Box BG3)
    - The Ruins of Myth Drannor (TSR, Inc.), 1993 (Box BG3)
    - The Ruins of Undermountain (TSR, Inc.), 1991 (Box BG3)
    - The Ruins of Undermountain II (TSR, Inc.), 1994 (Box BG3)
    - The Ruins of Zhentil Keep (TSR, Inc.), 1995 (Box BG72)
  - Gamma World, 27
    - Gamma World (TSR, Inc.), 1978 (Box BG13)
      By the creators of Dungeons and Dragons
    - Gamma World (TSR, Inc.), 1983 (Box BG13)
    - Gamma World (TSR, Inc.), 1986 (Box BG13)
  - Gangbusters, 28
    - Gangbusters: 1920's Role-Playing Adventure Game (TSR, Inc.), 1980 (Box BG16)
    - Gangbusters: 1920's Role-Playing Adventure Game New 3rd Edition (TSR, Inc.), 1982 (Box BG16)
  - Gazetteer, 29
    - Dawn of the Emperors: Thyatis and Alphatia (TSR, Inc.), 1989 (Box BG66)
      Dungeons & Dragons. Official Game Accessory.
  - Ghostbusters, 30
    - Ghostbusters: A Frightfully Cheerful Roleplaying Game (West End Games, Inc.), 1986 (Box BG19)
    - Ghostbusters: International: The Humorous Horror Roleplaying Game (West End Games, Inc.), 1989 (Box BG19)
  - Greyhawk (ADD), 31
    - From the Ashes (TSR, Inc.), 1992 (Box BG4)
    - The City of Greyhawk (TSR, Inc.), 1989 (Box BG4)
    - Wars (TSR, Inc.), 1991 (Box BG4)
    - World of Greyhawk (TSR, Inc.), 1980 (Box BG4)
    - World of Greyhawk (TSR, Inc.), 1983 (Box BG4)
  - Imperium, 32
    - Imperium: Empires in Conflict: Worlds in Balance (GDW), undated (Box BG81)
  - Indiana Jones, 33
    - The World of Indiana Jones (West End Games, Inc.), 1994 (Box BG1)
  - James Bond 007, 34
    - James Bond 007: Live and Let Die: An Action Episode Game (Victory Games, Inc.), 1985 (Box BG58)
    - James Bond 007: A View to A Kill: Role Playing in Her Majesty's Secret Service (Victory Games, Inc.), 1985 (Box BG48)
    - James Bond 007: Dr. No: Role Playing in Her Majest's Secret Service (Victory Games, Inc.), 1984 (Box BG48)
    - James Bond 007: For Your Information: Gamemaster Supplement: Role Playing in Her Majesty's Secret Service (Victory Games, Inc.), 1984 (Box BG49)
    - James Bond 007: Goldfinger II: The Man with the Midas Touch: Role Playing in Her Majesty's Secret Service (Victory Games, Inc.), 1985 (Box BG48)
    - James Bond 007: Goldfinger: Role Playing in Her Majesty's Secret Service (Victory Games, Inc.), 1983 (Box BG48)
    - James Bond 007: Live and Let Die: Role Playing in Her Majesty's Secret Service (Victory Games, Inc.), 1984 (Box BG48)
    - James Bond 007: Octopussy: Role Playing in Her Majesty's Secret Service (Victory Games, Inc.), 1983 (Box BG48)
    - James Bond 007: Role Playing in Her Majesty's Secret Service: Gamemaster Pack (Victory Games, Inc.), 1983 (Box BG48)
    - James Bond 007: The Complete Basic Set: Role Playing in Her Majesty's Secret Service (Victory Games, Inc.), 1983 (Box BG49)
    - James Bond 007: The Man with the Golden Gun: Role Playing in Her Majesty's Secret Service (Victory Games, Inc.), 1985 (Box BG48)
    - James Bond 007: Villians: Role Playing in Her Majesty's Secret Service (Victory Games, Inc.), 1986 (Box BG49)
    - James Bond 007: You Only Live Twice: Role Playing in Her Majesty's Secret Service (Victory Games, Inc.), 1984 (Box BG48)
  - Jovian Chronicles, 35
    - Cega Fleet Blueprint File for Jovian Chronicles (DreamPod 9, Inc.), 1999 (Box BG1)
    - Jovian Fleet Blueprint File for Jovian Chronicles (DreamPod 9, Inc.), 1998 (Box BG1)
  - Judge Dredd, 36
    - Judge Dredd: The Game of Crime-Fighting in Mega-City One (Games Workshop), 1982 (Box BG8)
    - Judge Dredd: The Role-Playing Game (Games Workshop), 1985 (Box BG8)
  - Legend of the Five Rings, 37
    - Legend of the Five Rings: City of Lies (Alderac Entertainment Group), 1996 (Box BG42)
    - Legend of the Five Rings: The Tomb of Iuchiban (Alderac Entertainment Group), undated (Box BG42)
    - The Battle of Beiden Pass (Five Rings Publishing Group Inc), 1996 (Box BG62)
      Legend of the Five Rings: Basic Training for the Armies of Rokugan
  - Lord of the Rings, 38
    - Middle Earth: War of the Ring: S.R. 1418 to 1419: based on J.R.R. Tolkien's The Ring Trilogy (Simulations Publications, Inc.), 1977 (Box BG37)
    - The Fellowship of the Ring: Based on the works of J.R.R. Tolkien (Iron Crown Enterprises, Inc.), 1983 (Box BG47)
  - Lords of Creation, 39
    - Lords of Creation (The Avalon Hill Game Company), 1983 (Box BG38)
    - Lords of Creation: The Yeti Sanction (The Avalon Hill Game Company), 1984 (Box BG38)
    - The Horn of Roland (The Avalon Hill Game Company), 1984 (Box BG38)
      A Lords of Creation Expansion Module
  - Marvel Super Heroes, 40
    - Marvel Super Heroes: Advanced Set (TSR, Inc.), 1986 (Box BG10)
    - Marvel Super Heroes: Deluxe City Campaign Set (TSR, Inc.), 1989 (Box BG10)
    - Marvel Super Heroes: The Heroic Role-Playing Game (TSR, Inc.), 1984 (Box BG10)
  - Mystara (ADD), 41
    - Karameikos: Kingdom of Adventure (TSR, Inc.), 1994 (Box BG72)
    - Mark of Amber (TSR, Inc.), 1995 (Box BG72)
    - Glantri: Kingdom of Magic (TSR, Inc.), 1995 (Box BG4)
      Advanced Dungeons and Dragons 2nd Edition; Includes audio CD
    - Hail the Heroes (TSR, Inc.), 1994 (Box BG4)
    - Night of the Vampire (TSR, Inc.), 1994 (Box BG4)
  - Odyssey (ADD), 42
    - Tale of the Comet (TSR, Inc.), 1997 (Box BG69)
  - Paratrooper, 43
    - Paratrooper (The Avalon Hill Game Company), 1986 (Box BG79)
  - Pendragon, 44
    - Pendragon: Chivalric Roleplaying in Arthur's Britain (Chaosium Inc.), 1985 (Box BG1)
  - Planescape (ADD), 45
    - A Player's Primer to the Outlands (TSR, Inc.), 1995 (Box BG67)
    - Hellbound: The Blood War (TSR, Inc.), 1996 (Box BG67)
    - Planes of Chaos (TSR, Inc.), 1994 (Box BG67)
    - Planes of Conflict (TSR, Inc.), 1995 (Box BG67)
    - Planes of Law (TSR, Inc.), 1995 (Box BG67)
    - Planescape (TSR, Inc.), 1994 (Box BG67)
  - Powers & Perils, 46
    - Powers & Perils (The Avalon Hill Game Company), 1983 (Box BG38)
    - Tower of the Dead (The Avalon Hill Game Company), 1984 (Box BG38)
      A trademark name for a Powers & Perils Adventure
  - Ravenloft (ADD), 47
    - A Light in the Belfry (TSR, Inc.), 1995 (Box BG68)
      Advanced Dungeons and Dragons; Includes audio CD